<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-20T16:10:33+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">I switched from the Android to the iPhone (iOS)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/11/13/I-switched-to-the-Iphone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I switched from the Android to the iPhone (iOS)" /><published>2018-11-13T20:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-13T20:04:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/13/I-switched-to-the-Iphone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/11/13/I-switched-to-the-Iphone.html">The reason I needed a new phone was, that I needed one, which was actually better than my phone I've been actually using. It was slow, unresponsive, laggy - I am talking about Meizu MX4. When Meizu came out, it beats all other phones in benchmarks. It was a beast. 

Before the Meizu MX4 I had small Samsung galaxy phone, I don't remember it's model name, it was just too many years in the past (which reminds me how old I actually am 😂). This samsung thing was my first touchable smartphone. From the beginning, I remember it was quite easy and pleasurable to use. I had installed some basic apps like messenger, facebook, instagram, google maps and some not too much resource hungry games. The problem with that phone was it has very little RAM or better said operating memory. I struggled with opening the gallery - the popup window said, there is no more memory or something like that. It was just...well... fu*king annoying. I had to go to Settings, then to the App management and kill some apps manually. This process of cleaning basically worked for me, but it was just too tedious and unnatural. I remember my friends opening their &quot;Multitasking view&quot; where all apps recently opened was listed in a horizontal manner and they swipe the items up and they gradually all disappeared. But it doesn't solve their problem either. 

![meizumx4](/assets/images/2/1.jpg)

# So let's decide
Samsung was not sufficient for me anymore. So I started to think about buying a new phone. It should have bigger memory, bigger screen and I also expected it to have a better camera. I was exploring the phone market, watching videos, reading reviews, comparing prices. iPhones and samsung phones were quite expensive, xiaomi phones had horrible camera (In that time - roughly mid 2016). One, though, took my attention with pretty body construction and only one bottom home button (no left and right controls) - it was Meizu MX4, in that time it was quite old model, but still powerful and it satisfied my requirements. From the camera samples I could tell images was pretty sharp with a bunch of  detail. Model was a few years old, but overrun some actual android models. I found it. I bough it. It came, and I kinda like it. First expression was extraordinary. Nice big black brick with huge lens on the back side, one home styled home button at the bottom. I was impressed.

# Everything went fine but...
But it was FlymeOS running as operating system inside the phone. I was excited about the FlymeOS at first, I thought developers making it better from the official android but... A lot of apps didn't work. I've got problem with file uploading, making photos inside apps. Then apps sometimes crashed. Not a good user experience at all.

# It was not that bad, it was not that good either
Photos were significantly better than the other phones were capturing. A lot of sharp details, huge 4K resolution. I expected better video quality, but what can we do. Another video disadvantage was the weird meizu 4K format which my computer was not able to recognize after importing.

It was quite fast, I used to home button and other special gestures to work with and that was pretty much it. I remember home button was real pleasure to work with. It served notification light, vibrates on tap. Recognize long tap, short tap, swipe upper from home button etc. It looked really intelligent and after a while, I was addicted to the home button. 
Battery life is another drawback of that phone. The capacity of the battery (I mean number of capacity XXXX mAh) was pretty normal, but in reality, it was horrible. Phone was discharging fast even when my display was shut off. When it was turned on - battery went down really fast. I could decrement that battery number at the top panel every minute ! It was really annoying. I want my phone battery to last at least day - it was not meizu's story.


# Meizu got old
There were significant scratches on the surface of back side of the phone, which was not nice at all. But that's not phone's fault - that scratches were my fault. Once I made a mistake by putting the phone on the table on the screen side. It makes also some scratches at home button which was fully touchable (no mechanical part) and it has just stopped working as it was expected. When it had happened I thought it was the end, but I get somehow to the app menu through turn off button and I was able to do at least something. It turns out Meizu had in their settings option to turn the software button on which was virtual navigation customizable button on your screen which you can moving around. I've set it up and was able to work with my phone which gave it some time before I'll throw it to the trash can.

# I want a new phone !
I didn't want to use that garbage anymore. It became so difficult to use that ugly slow device with horrible battery life. It started to be a ballast. It should be a pleasure to use a phone. It shouldn't be something you make an eyeroll every time you turn it on. 

# So I've started to search
At first, I was pretty much into android phones and I was quite distanced from the iPhones. For me, Iphones were quite overpriced. I was not familiar with spending like 400 euros for the phone. You can rather buy a solid computer for that money. I was not convinced with any android phone on the market with the price under 300€. Every phone had some drawback, bad review or some feature I didn't like. 
But then the iPhone SE popped up in my search result and I gave it a chance and clicked the link. It was older (2 year) model from iPhone series and... surprisingly, it met all my criteria. I watched so much youtube videos about this phone. Almost every person I've watched in a video was very happy with that small phone. Yes it was smaller than the other phones - which became my the biggest thing which I was afraid of - I was used to have phones with bigger screens.

![iphone se](/assets/images/2/3.jpg)

Everything else seems to be perfect. Camera, performance, battery life, easy to use (These are from user's reviews). My one fear was the display size. After one month of first seeing this phone I have finally bought it. 
I am using it for two months now and I can tell you I did a good trade. For 250€ I have everything I need from the ideal phone. Responsive, excellent camera (for that money), fast and reliable phone. Finally. 

![iphone se](/assets/images/2/2.jpg)

# Things I do like
- One clicky home buton (Someone hate it, someone love it)
- Size ! - Actually I like smaller size and I've got used to it
- AirDrop - I was astonished by simplicity and speed of sharing media between apple devices, for the first time, I felt like it was instant.
- bottom control panel (customizable)
- Camera quality, simplicity of the capturing app (Camera)
- Photos library (Albums, Places, Memories)
- iCloud
- Pretty fast touchID
- Screen watchtime and app time limitation (You get warning about spending more time than you set for the app or for the type of the app)

# Thing I don't like
- WIFI after turned off in control panel is actually in sleep mode and will turn on WIFI if there is connection available - you need to turn it off in the Settings
- exactly the same thing with bluetooth
- Music and file management

Conclusion
I purchased it two months ago and I don't refuse this buy.

![okay_gif](https://media.giphy.com/media/GCvktC0KFy9l6/giphy.gif)</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The reason I needed a new phone was, that I needed one, which was actually better than my phone I’ve been actually using. It was slow, unresponsive, laggy - I am talking about Meizu MX4. When Meizu came out, it beats all other phones in benchmarks. It was a beast.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hard times</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/23/Hard-times.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hard times" /><published>2018-10-23T12:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-23T12:20:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/10/23/Hard-times</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/23/Hard-times.html">&lt;p&gt;Everything written here was deleted. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Everything written here was deleted. :)</summary></entry></feed>